thedarkroom.com 2019-08-29

# The Darkroom's Privacy Policy

Effective as of Friday, May 25, 2018.

### **At The Darkroom, we are passionate about film and our community of film enthusiasts and your privacy is important to us.**

* * *

## Introduction

This Privacy Notice explains what information The Darkroom (“TheDarkroom,” “we,” “us,” or “our”) collects, uses, shares, retains, and protects, and the choices you have. This Privacy Notice applies only to the websites and online services (collectively the “Services”) where this Privacy Notice is posted. Your use of the Services is also subject to our [Terms of Use](https://www.snapfish.com/photo-gift/tac-overlay).

This privacy policy applies to all The Darkroom users worldwide. For users in the European Economic Area (EEA) and in Switzerland, The Darkroom complies with the principles of the U.S.-EU Privacy Shield Program and the U.S.-Swiss Privacy Shield Program, and has applied to participate in both programs. Under both programs, we are subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission, and we are liable for the unauthorized transfer to third parties of user personal data. For more information, see [https://privacvshiQld.gov](https://privacvshiqld.gov/).

WE ENCOURAGE YOU TO READ THIS PRIVACY NOTICE AND THE TERMS OF USE IN FULL TO UNDERSTAND OUR PRIVACY PRACTICES BEFORE USING OUR WEBSITE, AND SERVICES. BY USING OUR WEBSITE, PRODUCTS, AND SERVICES, YOU ACKNOWLEDGE YOU HAVE READ AND UNDERSTOOD THE PRACTICES DESCRIBED IN THIS PRIVACY NOTICE.

## About this Policy

This Policy relays the essential details pertaining to your personal data used by The Darkroom. It applies to all The Darkroom services, defined in our Terms and Conditions (“Terms”).

In time, we may develop new products or offer new services. If these new products and services cause any change to the way in which we collect or process your personal data, we will provide you with more information on the additional terms and policies.

The aim of this Policy is to:

  1. Ensure that you understand what personal data we collect about you, the reasons why we collect it, and who we share it with;
  2. Explain your rights and choices in relation to the personal data we collect and process about you and how we will protect your privacy.

We need to process your personal information in order to run our business and provide you with these Services. By accepting this Policy and the Terms, you are confirming that you have read and understand this Policy including how and why we use your information. If you do not accept this Policy, please remember that it is your choice whether you want to use The Darkrooms’ services.

## When do we collect your personal data and what exactly do we collect?

We collect personal information in the following ways:

  1. When you register with The Darkroom
  2. When you use any of our products or services

We collect personal information when you register with The Darkroom and when you use any of our products or services. Personal information is any information about you that is personally identifiable like your name, address, email address or phone number, and any other information that is not otherwise publicly available. If you order products or pay for services, we will need your shipping address, billing name and address, as well as the credit card number and expiration date.

## Automatically collected information

Our servers automatically collect the following information regarding devices that access our site or service: device characteristics (including device ID for mobile devices), operating system, browser type, IP address, username from stored cookies if present, dates and times of each login, page and image viewing statistics, and incoming and outgoing links. We also log the metadata associated with uploaded Images. We use this automatically collected anonymous data to analyze how our website is being used so as to keep it optimized, to determine the popularity and usefulness of various features, and to enable users with usernames to access their posts, albums, and membership information. We also use such data to enable us to comply with copyright law with 18 USC §22S8A (illegal content), and to respond to lawful requests by public authorities, including national security, courts, and law enforcement.

## Cookies

Like many websites, we use cookies to collect anonymous visitor information. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer’s hard drive and stored in your browser’s cache. They make it possible for us to store the contents of your shopping cart until you are ready to check out, recognize your browser when you visit and provide you with information about products that interest you. By doing this, we can personalize your return visits and save you time during checkout. If you disable cookies in your web browser, some features of our website will not function properly.

## How cookies are used

**Message Prompts and Logged in state  
**We employ popup messages throughout the site. We use cookies to ensure that they popups are only viewed a certain number of times per browser session. After each session, these cookies are deleted.

**Measuring Website Usage (Google Analytics)  
**We use Google Analytics software to collect information about how you use TheDarkroom.com. We do this to help make sure the site is meeting the needs of its users and to help us make improvements, for example improving site search. Google Analytics stores information about:

  * The pages you visit on The Darkroom.
  * How long you spend on each The Darkroom page .
  * How you got to the site.
  * What you click on while you’re visiting the site.

Learn more at <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>, and to opt out, visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

**YouTube Videos  
**We use YouTube to provide videos on some pages of the site. YouTube sets cookies when you visit one of these pages.

## What do we use your personal data for?

We use your personal information for the following general purposes:

  1. To fulfill your requests for products and services, administrative purposes;
  2. To improve our service; and
  3. To contact you about new products, sales, and announcements.

We also use anonymous information, such as that pertaining to web pages you’ve viewed, in order to analyze trends, track user’s movements, provide a better website experience, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. We do not use this data in a manner that would identify you personally.

## Sharing your personal data

Every now and then, The Darkroom will invite customers and the public to take part in surveys, promotions, and contests. The information we collect from these surveys, promotions, and contests may be matched with individual customer accounts and used by The Darkroom to improve your overall customer experience, we do not share this information with any third parties.

Under the following circumstances, we may be required to share your personal information:

  * If we respond to subpoenas, court orders or legal process, or if we need to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims;
  * If we believe it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of the The Darkroom Terms & Conditions or as otherwise required by law.
  * Restrict or inhibit any other user from using the site, including, without limitation, by means of “hacking” or defacing any portion of the site;

## Data access, retention & deletion

You have the right and ability to edit your member account information on our website at any time. You can opt in or out of receiving future communications of special offers and new product information, or you can unsubscribe by following instructions contained in the messages you receive. We do reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to the services The Darkroom provide, such as service announcements and administrative messages, that are considered part of your account membership. We do not offer you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving those messages.

We keep your personal data only as long as necessary to provide you with services that we provide. If you request, we will delete your personal data so that it no longer identifies you, unless, we are legally allowed or required to maintain certain personal data.

## Children’s Information

We do not target our website or products to children, and we will not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children without obtaining prior verifiable parental consent. If we become aware that a subscriber is under the age of 13 and has registered without prior verifiable parental consent, we will remove their personally identifiable information from our files.

## The safety of your personal data

We are committed to protecting our users’ personal data. We use a secure server (SSL) to encrypt your personal financial information. We use other physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect the security and confidentiality of the personal information we have collected, and to prevent unauthorized access to or disclosure of your personal information.

## Third Party Sites

Our websites may contain links to other websites for news and other information. Our Privacy Policy only applies to the website of The Darkroom, and we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other websites which are linked to or integrated with The Darkroom. You should check the privacy policies of those sites before providing your personal information to them. See our Terms and Conditions for additional information.

## Questions

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, you can contact us at:

The Darkroom  
946 Calle Amanecer # A, San Clemente, CA 92673

You may access and use the site solely for your personal, noncommercial use. Except as expressly authorized hereunder, the site may not be reproduced, duplicated, copied, sold, resold, visited, reverse-engineered or otherwise exploited for any commercial purpose without The Darkroom’s prior written authorization. We reserve the right to alter or discontinue the site, in whole or in part, at any time in The Darkroom’s sole discretion.
